谢谢 这儿有位安德鲁·杰克逊[20美元]
Hey, thank you. Here's an Andrew Jackson.
给我弄一床干净的被单
Make a clean set of sheets happen,
我就把你介绍给他双胞胎兄弟
I'll introduce you to his twin brother.
其实不用非得逗她 不过我又不会少块肉对吧
You don't have to do the banter, but what's it cost me?
曼尼 坐火车这主意太棒了
Manny, it was a great idea to come on the train.
铁路是体面旅行的最后一道堡垒了
Rail is a last bastion of respectable travel
现在机场真的是什么样的人都能去了
now that every airport has become a sweat-pant convention.
我们全家要去波特兰
We are all traveling to Portland
因为杰的前妻迪迪要再婚了
because Jay's ex-wife, Dede, is getting remarried.
我们好开心
We're so happy.
是为我们自己
For us.
这意味着我不用再付该死的赡养费了
It means the end of those damn alimony payments,
所以我要确保迪迪顺利完婚
so I'm gonna make sure Dede goes through with it.
只要"我愿意""我愿意""结束了"
It'll be, "I do", "I do", "I'm done".
兄弟 我们这趟火车上得做多少次抉择啊
Dude, how much choice action are we gonna get on this trip?
我正在调整我的期待值
I'm managing my expectations.
你一点也不了解火车吗
Don't you know anything about trains?
姑娘们都变疯了
Chicks go crazy.
颠簸会让她们兴奋
The vibrations get them all worked up.
而且她们无处可去 正好下手
Also, they're trapped, which is nice.
我们要去写给老妈的祝酒辞
We're just gonna go bang out this toast for Mom.
是啊 不能拖到最后再写
Yeah. Shouldn't have waited till the last minute.
正好可以让你分心 免得晕车
It'll be a nice distraction from your motion sickness.
没关系 只要火车前进时
It's good, as long as I'm not facing backwards
我不是背对着...天哪 不行
when the train is -- Oh, God, no.
带我走
Lead me.
好 我来吧
All right, I got it.
走吧 固定点
There you go. Fixed point.
我的天哪 不是吧
Oh, my God, it can't be.
什么 不是啦 不是秃头啦
What? No, it's not a bald spot.
我昨天晚上没睡好
I slept on it funny last night.
不是啦 两排后的那个家伙
No. The guy two rows back.
那是西蒙·黑
That's Simon Ha--
黑斯廷斯 我的...
Hastings. Oh, my --
你也是他粉丝吗
You're a fan of his, too?
他是我最喜欢的作家
He's my favorite author.
别告诉米奇尔 我读他上一本书的时候
Don't tell Mitchell, but I was so engrossed
因为太投入 有一天半忘了喂莉莉
in his last book, I didn't feed Lily for a day and a half.
等等
Wait a second.
西蒙·黑斯廷斯是
Simon Hastings is the genius behind
《锡尔弗敦》系列悬疑小说的天才作者
the Silverton mystery novels.
《仅限非会员》
"Dismembers Only."
《新鲜空气之死》
"A Death of Fresh Air."
全世界等
The world has been waiting
三部曲的最后一部
for the final book of the trilogy
得有10年了吧
for almost, what, 10 years?
我太迫不及待了 自己先写了同人小说
I missed it so much, I took a stab at writing fan fiction.
什么
What?
我把锡尔弗敦置身于房地产的悲惨世界
I put Silverton in the harrowing world of real estate
名字就叫《开放日·密闭之棺》
with "Open House, Closed Casket."
起鸡皮疙瘩了
Goose bumps.
很抱歉打扰您 但是您是我们最爱的作家
We hate to bother you, but you are our favorite author.
先生们 文字都是现成的
Gentlemen, the words are all out there.
我只是按能赚钱的方式排布了一下而已
I just arrange them in a financially rewarding way.
-滑稽 太滑稽了 -典型的黑斯廷斯
- Droll. Droll is what it is. - Classic Hastings.
您现在是在...
That by any chance isn't the --
写下一部锡尔弗敦的小说吗
the next Silverton novel, is it?
你们是说《云霄火车杀人事件》吗
You mean "Locomotive for Murder"?
太妙了
Crackerjack.
都还没出呢 我已经在为要读完它而伤感了
It's not even out yet, and I'm sad about finishing it.
希望不会让你们失望
Well, I hope you won't be disappointed.
很高兴认识你们
Lovely to meet you.
你一般是怎么写作的
What's your process?
人物只是通过你说话吗
Are the characters just speaking through you?
情节有多重要呢
How important is plot?
这样吧 你们安静地坐下来
Here's an idea -- how would you two like
读一读第一章怎么样
to sit quietly and read the first chapter?
什么
What?
-我的... -什么
- My... - What?
-天哪 -什么
- God. - What?
请放心
Rest assured.
我们会保护好您的宝贝
Your treasure is in good hands.
我们也是在艺术界混的
We are also members of the artistic community.
我是小丑
Clown.
我是魔术师
Magician.
不行
Nope.
为什么 我们在火车上
What? We're on a train,
我在享受这种浪漫的旅行方式啊
and I'm embracing a romantic style of travel.
我懂 我爱死了
I get it, and I love it.
维多利亚饮茶帽真不错
Wonderful Victorian tea hat.
谢谢 一流的旅行德比帽
Thank you. Top-notch travel derby.
女士 下午茶见
Ma'am. See you at high tea.
他的样子太娘了
He acts like someone with low "T".
我买口香糖的时候落了我的杂志了
Ugh, I forgot my magazines when I was buying gum.
一心两用实在太难了吧
Oh, it's hard to do two things at once.
你还有书吗
You got an extra book?
我在重读《简·爱》
Well, I'm re-reading "Jane Eyre",
但我行李架上还有本《安娜·卡列尼娜》
but I've got "Anna Karenina" on deck.
你的是什么
What you got?
《哈丽特飓风》 基本都是图片
"Hurricane Harriet". It's mostly pictures.
成交 你坐过去
Sold. Move over.
哈丽特是干嘛的
So, what's Harriet's deal?
她是个没头没脑的傻姑娘 总给人惹麻烦
She's a ditzy girl who causes problems for everyone,
但自己从来都不知道
but never realizes it.
听起来不太现实啊
Doesn't sound very realistic.
你们知道厕所在哪儿吗
Ah, do you guys know where the bathroom is?
在后面
Oh, back there.
不是那边吗
Isn't it that way?
没关系啦
Doesn't matter.
请出示头等座票
First-class ticket, please.
我只是来找厕所的
I just came looking for the bathroom.
我的票在我的座位上
My ticket is in my seat.
你知道我每天会听到多少人说这种话吗
Do you have any idea how many times a day I hear that?
坐回原位[回到自己的国家]去
Just go back where you came from.
叫我回去
Go back where I came from?
好吧
Okay.
我明白了
I see how it is.
所以哈丽特傻不愣登地把那些人送进熊洞了吗
So, Harriet just sent those people right into a bear cave?
她永远不知道自己在干什么
She never knows what she's doing.
好傻啊
What an idiot.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
介意我坐这儿吗
You mind if I sit here?
不啊
Uh, no.
你的笑容很美
You have a beautiful smile.
谢谢
Thanks.
大家都嘲笑我的帽子
They make fun of you for wearing your headgear,
但是现在看看吧
but, hey, look at me now.
出示一下票
Tickets?
是啊
Oh, yeah.
亲爱的 我的票在你那里吗
Uh, honey, do you have my ticket?
没有啊
No.
我很肯定我把我的票给你了 宝贝
I'm pretty sure I gave you my ticket, babe.
抱歉 宝贝 回站票车厢去
Sorry, babe. Back to coach.
我原谅你
I forgive you.
来找我
Come find me.
老妈一向自由自在无拘无束
"Mom has always been a free spirit."
她也帮忙释放了酒瓶里的冤魂
"She has also helped to free a lot of spirits from bottles
因为这女人是个酒鬼 记好咯
'cause the woman's a boozehound!" Hello!
我不会写这个的
Yeah, I'm not gonna put that in.
这个怎么样
Uh, how about this one?
她的巧克力豆饼干的秘诀是
"The secret to her chocolate chip cookies
撒一小撮盐
was a dash of salt --"
和两大勺疯狂 因为这位女士心态失衡
"And two scoops of crazy because the lady's imbalanced."
记好咯
Hello!
克莱尔 是要祝福她 不是要苛责她
Claire, this is toast, not a roast.
你不舒服是因为这是你这辈子
Are you uncomfortable because, for the first time in your life,
第一次要变直[率]了吗
you have to be the straight man?
记好咯
Hello!
老说"记好咯"也不会让挖苦人的话变有趣的
Saying "Hello" doesn't make mean things funny.
我喜欢
I like it.
做决定的又不是你
Well, you don't get to decide.
为什么是你
How come you get to decide?
因为妈妈让我说祝酒词 不是你
'Cause Mom asked me and not you.
叫你来是因为我有负罪感
I included you because I felt bad.
好吧 我不在乎
That's fine. I don't care.
你自己搞定吧
You can do it yourself.
-我不在意 -克莱尔
- I don't care. - Claire.
等等
Wait.
不
Nope.
给你20块
This is a $20.
待会我妻子来了之后
When my wife shows up later,
"冰茶"就是威士忌的代号
"Iced tea" means Scotch.
外公 你会不会觉得外婆请你
Grandpa, do you think it's weird
参加她的婚礼很奇怪
Nana invited you to her wedding?
我觉得这是有史以来迪迪做出的最正常的事
I think it's the least-weird thing Dede's ever done.
如果她那么糟糕 你为什么还娶她
Well, if she was so bad, why'd you ever marry her?
我们当时都很年轻
We were young.
她很漂亮 但她一直疯个没完
She was cute, but the constant nuttiness of Dede
把我累坏了 简直都不想活了
wore me down, robbed me of my will to live.
有一天 她把我逼得受不了了
One day, she pushed me off the edge.
我从家里跑了出来
I ran out of the house.
他们在当地消防局找到了裸身的我
They found me shirtless in the local fire station.
不好意思
Excuse me.
你说的这位迪迪
This, uh, Dede that you're speaking of --
是不是迪迪·普里契特
um, is that Dede Pritchett, by chance?
你认识她吗
Do you know her?
她要嫁的人是我父亲
She's marrying my father.
不会吧
You're kidding.
真的 我们就是在去婚礼的路上
No. We're traveling to the wedding right now...
如果还会有婚礼的话
if there is one.
我得给爸打个电话
I've got to call Dad.
我早说了那女人不正常
I told you that woman was off.
小费还是改成2块好了
I'm gonna need $18 back.
不好意思
Uh, excuse me.
你好 海斯廷斯先生
Uh, hi, Mr. Hastings.
你知不知道 有没有开发出一种药
Um, do you know -- have they developed a cure yet?
治什么用的
For what?
破碎的心灵 因为我们俩的心都爽炸了
A blown mind -- because we have two of them.
你们太好了
You're too kind.
-谢谢 -谢谢
- Oh, thank you. - Oh, thank you.
我们就是超想知道列车长是怎么
Well, we are just dying to know how the conductor got
从车头来到车尾杀了大使
all the way from the front to the back, kill the ambassador,
还不被人发现的
and not be seen?
控制室有一个应急出口
There's an escape hatch in the control room.
他爬上去 从列车顶部
He climbs up, crawls his way across
爬到守车
the top of the train to the caboose.
他穿了磁性鞋 双脚牢牢吸在车顶
There, his feet firmly planted, thanks to magnetic shoes,
他倒挂着身子 向大使开枪
he hangs down, shoots the ambassador,
再按原路爬了回去
then crawls back the way he came.
太巧妙了
That is so ingenious.
他是怎么没被摄像头拍到的
How does he avoid the video cameras?
-对啊 -你说什么
- Yeah. - I beg your pardon.
车顶上的
On top of the train.
他坐的火车没装摄像头
He's on a train that doesn't have any cameras.
现在的火车都有了 老大
Oh, no, they all have cameras now -- Big Brother.
我刚在《铁路世界》的一篇文章上看到的
I just read an article about it in Rail World,
就是你座位口袋里那本杂志
the magazine in your seat pocket --
还看了一篇对业余列车长凡莱丽·柏帝内的采访
also a great interview with amateur conductor
写得可好了
Valerie Bertinelli.
如果这是真的 那谋杀不可能完成
Well, if that's true, then the murder isn't possible.
如果大使还活着
And if the ambassador is still alive,
锡尔弗顿就没理由去尼日利亚
then there's no reason for Silverton to be in Nigeria.
要是这样的话 他就不会参加行动
And if that's the case, he's not at the coup,
也就是说整件事都行不通了
which means the whole thing doesn't work.
我的上帝 我没法出书了
Dear God, I have no book.
我没法出书了
I have no book!
好后悔我还把错字圈出来了
Now I wish I hadn't circled the typos.
我还在这做什么 去找他呀
What are you still doing here? Go find him.
我不知道
I don't know.
快去啊 这个爱情故事
Come on, it's a better love story
比你看的要精彩
than the one you're reading.
你美丽 高贵 聪明
You're the beautiful, high-class, smart girl,
而他是个穷小子 跟一群流浪汉
and he's the poor boy duct-taping his shoes
以车厢为家
with a bunch of hobos in coach.
票价也就差20块
It's a $20 difference.
艾丽克斯 你能行的
Alex, you got this.
男生为火车疯狂
Trains make guys crazy.
你什么时候坐过火车
When were you ever on a train?
在拉斯维加斯 我坐火车去取的行李
In Vegas, between my plane and the luggage area.
被托运到别的地方去了
Stuff went down.
好吧 我去了
Fine. I'll go for it.
等等
Oh, wait.
别戴帽子
Nope.
曼尼喜欢戴帽子 对吧
Manny likes hats, doesn't he?
某人还对他有好感哦
Ooh, someone's still got a crush.
我并不以此为傲
I'm not proud of it.
试过要放下的
I tried to get past it.
不过 火车嘛 你懂的
But, you know, trains.
我觉得你看着挺可爱的 他应该也会这么想
Well, I think you look cute, and I bet he would, too.
嘿 小色鬼们
Hey, pervs.
我猜猜 钓妹子钓得肩膀都酸了吧
Let me guess -- shoulders tired from striking out so hard?
时间还早呢
It's still early.
我看到一枚十分硬币
Ooh, I see a dime piece over there.
就是说她是个十分妹子
That means she's a 10.
我知道 我也会说暗语
Yeah. I speak d-bag.
卢克 她年纪有点大吧
Luke, she's a little old.
詹妮弗·洛佩兹都快90岁了
Hey, Jennifer Lopez is like 90.
我偶尔还会把抱枕想象成她呢
Doesn't mean I don't pretend she's my pillow every now and then.
怎么会有妹子看上他呢
How does he have prospects?
希望你能好受些
If it makes you feel any better,
那边的小家伙可喜欢你了
that one's got a big crush on you.
我并该感到不意外
I guess I shouldn't have been surprised.
我总能感觉到艾丽克斯对我的些许热情
I've always sensed a little heat from Alex.
女人要是不想钻进男人的外套
A woman doesn't compliment a man on his hat
怎么会称赞他的帽子呢
unless she wants to get into his blazer.
和好吧
Peace offering?
多谢
Thank you.
听着 很抱歉我跟你说
Look, I'm sorry I told you
妈妈选我致祝酒词而不是你
that Mom picked me for the toast and not you.
我只是觉得
It's just that
我和她一直有一种很特殊的联系
I've always had a special relationship with her.
当然了 就像女巫和飞猴的关系一样
Sure, like the one between a witch and her flying monkey.
别这样
Don't do that.
别用《绿野仙踪》酸我
Don't use "The Wizard of Oz" against me.
妈妈爱摆布你
Mom manipulates you.
她利用你来对付我们其他人
She uses you against the rest of us.
真不知道你在说什么
I have no idea what you're talking about.
天 我想个例子
Oh, God, if only I could think of an example.
等等 这是三十个例子之一
Oh, wait, here's one of 30.
她翘了艾丽克斯的毕业典礼却没告诉我们
She blew off Alex's graduation, but she didn't tell us.
她逼你来说
She made you do it
这样我们所有人就都会指责你而不是她
so we would all dump on you instead of her.
这次她不让我致祝酒词
And now she bans me from giving a toast,
我们俩却在为此争执
and we're fighting about it.
得了吧 她把你当肉盾利用
Come on. She's using you like a human shield.
这算是健康的关系吗
Does that seem like a healthy relationship?
好好想想吧
Why don't you give that some thought
顺便再给我倒一杯来
while you're getting me a refill?
你什么时候喝光的
When did you even drink that?
明明一直在说话
You've been talking the whole time.
好吧 根本没信号
Fine. I don't get anything.
别 伙计
No... Hey, pal.
先别给你爸打电话
Before you call your dad,
我刚才关于迪迪的言论
what I was saying about Dede
只是在掩饰而已 因为我失去了
was me just covering up because I lost
最美好 最持重的人
the greatest, most stable person I've ever known.
可你看上去很生气
But you seemed so angry.
因为我放不下她
It's because I can't get over her.
我试了所有方法
I've tried everything --
理疗 吃药 电击
therapy, pills, electricity.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我只是太想她了
It's just that I miss her so much.
我将见到世界上最幸运的男人
I-I'm gonna see the luckiest man in the world
迎娶世界上最美好的女人
marry the most wonderful woman in the world,
而我却孤身一人
and I have nobody.
不好意思 先生
Excuse me, sir.
这位女士说她是你妻子
This woman says she's your wife.
我不认识她
Never seen her before.
但我认识这位 我儿子 米奇尔
But here's someone I do know -- my son, Mitchell.
米奇尔和迪迪是密友
Mitchell and Dede are great pals.
给这些朋友介绍一下你妈妈
Tell these lovely folks about your mother.
她是个腹黑的女魔头
She's a scheming dragon woman
拼命摧毁她身边的所有人
hell-bent on destroying everyone around her.
你一定要选在今天觉悟吗
You pick today to realize that?!
不客气
You're welcome.
我终于让他看清了
I finally got him to see Mom
妈妈真正的样子 险恶的老疯子
for who she really is -- a nasty, old nutjob.
但她现在是其他人的烦恼了
But she's someone else's problem now, huh?
等一下 你知道吗
Wait a minute. You know what?
我也不认识这些人
I don't know these people, either.
走吧 失陪
Let's go. Excuse me.
失陪
Pardon us.
你好 我叫海莉
Hi. I'm Haley.
很高兴见到你 我是个大骗子
Pleasure. I'm a massive fraud.
听起来你需要喝一杯
Sounds like you need a drink.
我不觉得那是个好主意
I'm not sure that's a good idea.
我以前会用...
I used to have something of a...
来嘛 我觉得一个人喝很奇怪
Oh, come on. I feel weird drinking alone.
我不觉得 我只是想让他买单
I don't. I just wanted him to pay.
上一次我喝那么醉的时候
The last time I was this bladdered,
我暴揍了萨曼·拉什迪那个自命不凡的家伙
I parked my fist right in Salman Rushdie's smug gob.
你知道阿黛尔吗
Do you know Adele?
-他在这里 -过来看一眼
- There he is. - Hey. Just checking in. Hi.
在庆祝自己解决了难题吗
Ooh, celebrating solving your problem?
在才思枯竭中煎熬了十年之后
After 10 years of paralyzing writer's block,
我以为自己终于能够
I at last felt that I was drinking
直接获得灵感缪斯的哺育
directly from the teat of the muse.
但她不是缪斯
But she was no muse.
她是妖魔
She was a succubus.
真有语言天分
Such a gift for language.
在下一站 我就要烧掉这本书
At the next stop, I'm going to burn this book.
太有种了
That is bad-ass.
不 什么
No! What?
是的 这将会是我职业生涯的最后一笔
Yes. It will be the last act of my career.
别算上在波特兰的专题讨论会
Well, not counting the panel discussion in Portland.
取消掉就太无礼了
It would be rude to cancel.
招待会上有葡萄酒和奶酪
There's a wine-and-cheese reception.
你必须写完它
You have to finish.
如果我们能证明它可行呢
What if we proved it could happen?
也许还有别的方法
Maybe there's another way
能让杀人犯去到最后一节车厢再回来
for the murderer to get to the caboose and back.
火车上全都是
I've filled the train with characters
无法知道工程师留下邮件的角色
who cannot know that the engineer has left his post.
没有希望了
It's hopeless!
等等 我们停下来了吗
Wait. Did we just stop?
-不 我不觉得 -没有
- No. I don't think so. - No. Mnh-mnh.
看看加利福尼亚多美呀
Look how beautiful California is.
乘坐火车最美妙的地方
The best part about taking the train,
就像我常常跟 孩子们说的一样
as I often do for my work with, uh, the children,
就是风景了
has got to be the scenery.
是吗
Yeah?
你最喜欢的景点是哪里
What's your favorite spot?
我觉得必须是...
Well, I'd have to say the spot where, uh...
格兰德河倾入苏必利尔湖的景色
the Rio Grande pours into Lake Superior.
我好像没见过
Huh. I don't think I've seen that.
能容许我失陪一小会吗
Can you excuse me for just a pinch?
当然
Sure.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
让自己变得丰盈 那样才能更进一步
Getting swollen 'cause that's how you close.
顺便说一句
Oh, by the way,
要是一条领带挂在门前 那就是卢克开始得分了
if you see a tie on our door, Luke's starting to score.
现在就为你加油有点困难
It's a little hard to root for you right now.
我们说到哪了
So, where were we?
这是你第一次来大苏尔海岸线吗
Is this your first time seeing the Central Coast, Big Sur?
不 不是的 小姐
No, it's not, little miss.
我等不及要观赏今晚安第斯山脉上的日落了
I can't wait to watch the sunset over the Andes tonight.
虽然现在我面前的景色也很秀美
Not like my view right now isn't fantastic.
你很可爱
You're cute.
如果你喜欢
You know, if you're into it,
我想我可以给你看点东西
I think I could show you a few things.
这里有点吵
Uh... It's a little loud in here.
也许我们该去个安静的地方
Maybe we should go somewhere more quiet.
没问题
Sure.
真的吗
Really?
火车
Trains.
你很专注
You're so serious.
我想尽可能地画出你的美
I want to make sure I capture your beauty.
我可以看看吗
Can I see yet?
希望你喜欢
I hope you like it.
他不是艺术家 谁在乎呢
So, he's not an artist. Who cares?
头等舱的人以为
People in first class think they have it made
提早登舱和稍稍干净一点的座位就代表着成功
with their early boarding and their slightly cleaner seats.
但他们不懂生活
But they don't know what living is.
我愿为上卫生间排长队
I'll take a long line for the bathroom
如果那卫生间在天堂
if that bathroom is in heaven.
很高兴你能来这里
I'm so glad you came back here.
我也是
Me too.
感觉很奇怪
This feels weird.
你有包间吗
Do you have a compartment?
我有 但你要怎么过来呢
I do, but how will you get up there?
我会有办法的
I'll find a way.
我答应你
I promise.
另外 我在18B间
Oh, by the way, I'm in compartment 18B,
也就是"男孩你太可爱了"
as in, "Boy, are you cute."
我真是傻 快走吧
Idiot. Just keep walking.
可以了
Got it.
我有信号了
I have a signal.
-太好了 -各位 各位 别这样
- Oh, good. - Guys, guys, guys, come on.
我们唯一需要的信号是这个
The only signal we need is this.
我的孩子们 他们并不讨厌迪迪
My kids in the back -- they don't hate Dede.
他们在为婚礼准备烧烤
They're preparing a roast for the wedding.
那是我们家表达爱的方式
That's how our family shows love.
你们会在宴会上尝到的
You'll get a taste of it at the reception.
你们是哪国人 意大利吗
What are you, Italian?
我们会做全套的
We'll do a whole thing,
除非你们学《教父》扫射现场
unless you shoot the place up first.
看到没 就是这样
Oh. See? That kind of stuff.
杰·普里契特 我要掐死你
Jay Pritchett, I am going to strangle you!
我不知道为什么你假装
I don't know why you're pretending
你不认识我
that you don't know me,
但我敢肯定你是为了什么愚蠢又自私的理由
but I'm sure it's for some stupid and selfish reason!
她真的是你妻子吗
She really is your wife?
暂时是
For now.
很快 你就会坐上一辆
Pretty soon, you're gonna be getting on a train
开往我下场婚礼的列车
to my next wedding.
你快逼疯我了
You're driving me insane.
我懂了
Oh, I see what's going on.
别听她的
Don't listen to her.
迪迪并没有疯 你疯了
Dede's not crazy. You are.
当然 也可以
Sure. That works.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是卡尔
Oh, I'm Carl.
我父亲要跟迪迪结婚
Uh, my father's marrying Dede.
是的 他要结婚 一起庆祝吧
Yes, he is, and let's celebrate.
喝什么我买单
Drinks on me.
没关系了
What the heck.
再次 很抱歉我让你们担心迪迪的事
And, again, I'm sorry to have worried you guys about Dede.
别这样
Oh, please.
卡尔的爸爸也不是什么善茬
It's not like Carl's father is such a prize.
怎么了
What?
他打砸抢烧了你妈妈的房子
He snapped and burned your mom's house down.
她在开玩笑
She's kidding.
我们也准备了烧烤
Uh, we're doing a roast, too.
是啊 你妈妈就差点变烧猪了
Yeah, right. Your mother was almost a roast.
我们要证明这场犯罪是可行的
We needed to prove that the crime was feasible,
所以我要假扮工程师兼杀人犯的角色
so I would play the role of engineer/murderer.
而我要假扮其他所有人的角色
And I would play the role of everyone else.
我家乡剧院出品的《罗宾汉》
When my hometown theater's production of "Robin Hood"
缺女主演的时候 我除了扮演修士
was lacking a leading lady, I stepped into the role
还顺带出演了一下女仆玛丽安的角色
of Maid Marian in addition to playing the Friar.
-塔克吗 -其实本没有必要
- Tuck? - Didn't have to.
戏服掩饰得很好
The costume hid it quite nicely.
我周日了狗了
Sunday dinner!
什么
What?!
那个土耳其大使的保镖
The Turkish ambassador's bodyguard
得到命令要干掉所有可疑人员
was instructed to neutralize anyone who looks suspicious.
什么
What?
土耳其语 从头开始的意思
It's Turkish for "From the top."
你回来前我实在是太无聊了
I have a lot of downtime while you're resetting.
汪
Woof!
难道你忘了马克西姆·杜维纳伯爵
Did you forget Count Maxim du Vernay
带了他的沙皮犬吗
brought his service Shar-pei?
说实话 那部分我没读
If I'm being honest, I skimmed that part.
重来
Again!
你好 准备好了吗
Hi. You ready for me?
我自认为已经查了所有该知道的东西
I believe I've Googled everything I need to know.
那我们就开始吧
So, let's get started.
这是加利福尼亚
This is California.
苏必利尔湖在这里 横跨...
Lake Superior is here, all the way across --
你在脱我的鞋吗
Are you trying to take off my shoe?
我以为你想给我看什么东西
I thought you wanted to show me things.
是啊
I do.
我是个地理老师 孩子 你真需要补补课了
I'm a geography teacher, and, boy, do you need one.
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding me?
如果她的新丈夫是个纵火犯
If her new husband is an arsonist,
那你们必须告诉她
you guys have to tell her.
各位 冷静点 那家伙烧过一座房子
Everybody, calm down. The guy burned down one house.
他没进监狱 说明他在政府有人
He's not in jail, so he's got the government's A-okay.
我最近发觉妈妈有点问题
I recently discovered I have some issues with Mom,
但我爱她
but I love her.
我不希望她在一所燃烧的房子里醒来
I don't want her to wake up in a burning house
尽管她婚后你就不用再付赡养费了
just so you don't have to pay alimony.
我也爱妈妈 通常情况下
I love Mom, too... usually.
但如果婚礼取消
But if this wedding doesn't happen,
你知道未来十年她会去哪
you know where she's gonna end up in 10 years --
不是你家就是我家
su casa or...my...casa.
而且 他的第一任妻子令他发了疯
Besides, the first wife obviously drove the guy nuts.
我们怎么知道你母亲...
How do we know your mother's gonna --
老天
Oh, geez.
卢克 你学得可真快
Luke, you're such a quick learner.
谢谢 我原来不知道这地方就在那儿
Thanks. I had no idea that was there.
请进
Come in.
是你吗
Is that you?
我马上就出来
I'll be out in a second.
真是太淘气了
This is so naughty.
我打算去见艾丽克斯 劝她放弃
I was going to see Alex and let her down easy.
她是我的家人 这是乱伦
I mean, she's family. It's taboo.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我不该评头论足的 尤其是在火车上
I shouldn't be judgy, especially when, you know, trains.
真黑 我喜欢
Ooh. Dark. I like it.
我是来拒绝你的[失去性致]
I-I was going to let you down!
你做到了
You sure did!
你的帽子太显眼了
Well, your hat was garish.
请问
Excuse me.
你们中是否有人看见
Have any of you guys seen the guy
刚才跟我一起跳舞的人
I was dancing with earlier?
结果是 我离开后詹姆斯就下车了
So, it turns out James got off right after I left him.
说句题外话 我的钱包不见了
On a possibly unrelated note, my wallet is gone.
火车
Trains.
黑斯廷斯先生 我们做到了
Mr. Hastings, we did it.
我们到了厨房又回来了 没被别人发现
We made it to the caboose and back without being seen.
你设计的情节是可行的
Your book works.
真不敢相信 你们确定吗
I can't believe it. Are you sure?
-是的 -是的 结合了渺小 智慧和伪装
- Yes! - Yes. It's a combination of slithering, clever disguise,
不是对您的写作提什么建议
and not to write the book for you,
但如果伯爵有只义肢 会很有帮助的
but it would help if the Count had a wooden hand.
我也正有此意
Well, I was sort of in that area anyway.
真是万分感谢
A thousand thank-yous.
锡尔弗敦活下来了
Silverton lives!
太棒了
Yay!
你们几个在研究书的事吧
Hi. Oh, you guys are doing that book thing, right?
-是啊 -不知道是否能帮上忙
- Yeah. - Well, I don't know if this helps at all,
不过刚才我跟司机谈过
but I was just talking to the engineer.
结果是 他不能离开驾驶室
It turns out he can't leave the controls
因为那个叫驾驶失知制动装置的东西
because of what's called a dead man's switch.
如果他离开那里 整辆火车就会停下来
If he takes his foot off of it, the whole train stops.
不用谢我
Anyway, you're welcome.
如果司机不能离开驾驶室 那么...
If the engineer can't leave the controls, then...
他就不能实施谋杀
He can't commit the murder.
结束了
It's over.
黑斯廷斯 我们很抱歉
Hastings, we are so sorry.
是时候摆脱这
It's time to rid myself
五百页的废纸了
of this 500-hundred page stain.
等等 不要
Wait! No! No, no, no, no!
-不 不要 -该死 怎么打不开
- No! No, no! - Open, damn you!
等等
Wait! Wait!
那是火车尾吗
Is that the back of the train?
没错 这就是著名的"马蹄转角"
Yep. This is the famous horseshoe turn.
在美国境内只有两处
Only two of them in the continental United States,
其中一处就是在加利福尼亚
one of which is here in California,
而加利福尼亚在北美
which is in North America.
呜呼哀哉 现在我都知道了
Sadly, I know all of this now.
就是这
That's it.
司机从没离开驾驶室
The engineer -- he never has to leave the controls.
他等到了马蹄转角
He waits for the horseshoe turn.
就把伯爵一枪干死在最后一节车厢里
Then he plugs the Earl in the caboose.
听起来有点怪
I heard it.
这简直太秒了
This is brilliant!
真不敢相信你们两个小丑救了我的书
I can't believe you two clowns have saved my book.
其实 只有我是小丑
Actually, it's just one clown.
我是魔术师
One magician.
-老妈 -好啊 老妈
- Hey, Mom! Hi! - Hi, Mom!
原有的家人们 你们好
Well, hello, original family.
迪迪 我们有事要告诉你
Dede, we have something we have to tell you.
我知道有更委婉的方式可以用
Now, I know there's a delicate way to say this.
只不过我没去想
Just can't think of it.
你的未婚夫是个纵火犯
Your fiancé's a pyro.
他烧了他前妻的房子
He burnt down his ex-wife's house.
你们三个就想毁了我的好日子
It's just like you three to try to ruin my big day.
妈妈 我们认为你应该知道
Mom, we just thought you should know.
杰瑞什么都告诉我了
Jerry told me everything.
相信我 那个女人罪有应得
Trust me. She had it coming.
那女人是个疯子
The woman's "Cah-razy."
所以你不介意他是个纵火犯吗
So, you're okay he's a firebug?
他充满激情 杰
He's passionate, Jay.
他知道该怎么宣泄自己的情感 不像你
He knows how to express his feelings, unlike you.
如果你也能烧了我们的房子
Maybe if you had burned our house down,
或许我们现在还在一起
we'd still be together.
是我的错 你说得对 迪迪
My mistake. You're right, Dede.
很好 妈妈 婚礼上见
Great, Mom. See you at the wedding.
再见 克莱尔 我为你安排的座位
Bye. Claire, you're not mad at me
你不会生气吧
about your seating arrangements?
为什么生气 我坐在哪里
Why? Where am I sitting?
米奇尔 你来告诉她
Mitchell, tell her.
我挂了
Got to run.
你不会坐在家人桌上
You're not sitting at the family table.
记好咯
Hello!
菲尔寄给我他的锡尔弗敦同人小说
Phil sent me his Silverton fan fiction,
《开放日·密闭之棺》
"Open House, Closed Casket."
他抬头看见这伟大房间中
"He looked up at the pristine crown molding
原本的天花板线 呼吸到
in the great room and felt the breeze
刚修缮过的中央空调中排放出的空气
of the recently updated central air.
克拉泽斯夫人 在这令人向往的小房里
'Mrs. Coruthers, just as this desirable corner lot
被劈成两半了 克拉泽斯先生亦是如此
was split in half, so, too, is Mr. Coruthers.'
寡妇喘着气靠在
The widow gasped and steadied herself
花岗岩厨房岛旁 恰如其分地表现出
on the granite kitchen island, a fitting metaphor
她内心的孤独感 尽管她正路过
for how alone she felt, despite being walking distance
生机勃勃的商业区和优秀的学校
to a vibrant shopping district and wonderful schools."
这两周我一直在躲着他
I've been avoiding him for the last two weeks.
别接电话
Don't answer that!